[
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, Dr. Haber does NOT describe George Orr as",
    "a": "unusually tall",
    "b": "wearing ordinary clothing",
    "c": "slightly undernourished",
    "d": "having a conservative haircut",
    "e": "keeping his beard short",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, when does Orr claim the world ended?",
    "a": "February 1997",
    "b": "May 1998",
    "c": "April 1998",
    "d": "March 1998",
    "e": "April 1997",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, according to Orr, how did the world end at the beginning of the novel?",
    "a": "asteroid impact",
    "b": "global nuclear war",
    "c": "contagious plague",
    "d": "robot takeover",
    "e": "alien invasion",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, how does Orr try to suppress dreaming?",
    "a": "drinking alcohol",
    "b": "taking drugs",
    "c": "meditating",
    "d": "starving",
    "e": "overexerting himself",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, what is William Haber’s profession?",
    "a": "neurosurgeon",
    "b": "dream specialist",
    "c": "medical technician",
    "d": "bioengineer",
    "e": "neurobiologist",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, who remembers the world before it supposedly ended?",
    "a": "Penny Crouch",
    "b": "George Orr",
    "c": "Mannie Ahrens",
    "d": "Heather Lelache",
    "e": "William Haber",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, Heather Lelache thinks of Orr as",
    "a": "“Mr. Morr Morr”",
    "b": "“Mr. Borr”",
    "c": "“Mr. Either Orr”",
    "d": "“Mr. Neither Norr”",
    "e": "“Mr. Saviorr”",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, Heather Lelache refers to Orr as “the",
    "a": "kindest person”",
    "b": "smartest person”",
    "c": "calmest person”",
    "d": "strongest person”",
    "e": "best person”",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Lathe of Heaven, George Orr acts as the",
    "a": "villain",
    "b": "hero",
    "c": "orbital character",
    "d": "anti-hero",
    "e": "supporting character",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, which of the following descriptions is NOT used by Le Guin to describe Dr. Haber?",
    "a": "opaque dark eyes",
    "b": "short-statured",
    "c": "bay-maned",
    "d": "white-toothed",
    "e": "red-brown beard",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, which of the following animals is used to describe Dr. Haber?",
    "a": "a dog",
    "b": "a bear",
    "c": "a gorilla",
    "d": "a jellyfish",
    "e": "an elephant",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the beginning of The Lathe of Heaven, Dr. Haber’s office is on the 63rd floor of the",
    "a": "HURAD",
    "b": "Deparment of Public Works",
    "c": "US Capitol",
    "d": "Willamette East Tower",
    "e": "World Planning Center",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, after one of Orr’s dreams, Dr. Haber becomes Director of the Oregon",
    "a": "Oneirological Institute",
    "b": "Brain Institute",
    "c": "Psychological Institute",
    "d": "Neurological Institute",
    "e": "Dream Institute",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, manipulating George and his dreaming ability, Dr. Haber consciously eliminates",
    "a": "sexism",
    "b": "alien threats",
    "c": "terrorism",
    "d": "drug abuse",
    "e": "racism",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, Dr. Haber ends up becoming the director of",
    "a": "Health Utilization: Research and Development",
    "b": "Human Utility: Research and Development",
    "c": "Holistic Unity: Research and Development",
    "d": "Humanity Unified: Research and Development",
    "e": "Human Universe: Research and Development",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Heather Lelache’s occupation?",
    "a": "shop owner",
    "b": "psychiatrist",
    "c": "musician",
    "d": "lawyer",
    "e": "physician",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "When does Heather Lelache FIRST become entwined in the struggle between Orr and Haber?",
    "a": "when she witnesses one of Orr’s dreams",
    "b": "when she is dreamt out of existence",
    "c": "when she falls in love with Orr",
    "d": "when she is employed by Haber",
    "e": "when she becomes one of Haber’s patients",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does Orr go when he desperately tries to escape Haber’s influence?",
    "a": "Lelache’s home",
    "b": "a rural farmhouse",
    "c": "a cabin in the woods",
    "d": "a ghost town",
    "e": "a secluded bunker",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Orr dreams Heather Lelache out of existence when Haber urges him to",
    "a": "end racism",
    "b": "make himself more powerful",
    "c": "eliminate overpopulation",
    "d": "cure all diseases",
    "e": "rid the world of crime",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following descriptions BEST characterizes Heather Lelache at the end of the novel?",
    "a": "fierce and recalcitrant",
    "b": "callous and unfeeling",
    "c": "unaggressive and timid",
    "d": "friendly and sympathetic",
    "e": "silent and mournful",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following descriptions does NOT characterize Mannie Ahrens?",
    "a": "He is one of the few people to provide Orr with peace and privacy.",
    "b": "He is a member of the Aldebaranian species.",
    "c": "He works as an elevator guard.",
    "d": "He calls a medic for Orr after a possible drug overdose.",
    "e": "He helps Lelache when she is searching for Orr.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which time period does Mannie Ahrens MOST strongly embody?",
    "a": "the 1970s",
    "b": "the 1960s",
    "c": "the 1950s",
    "d": "the 1930s",
    "e": "the 1940s",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do Mannie Ahrens and Asfah play a similar role in Orr’s life?",
    "a": "They both employ Orr at different times in the novel.",
    "b": "They both show Orr critical acts of kindness.",
    "c": "They both give Orr valuable items as gifts.",
    "d": "They both have disagreements with Orr.",
    "e": "They both teach Orr important life lessons.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which theme does Mannie Ahrens most strongly symbolize?",
    "a": "shifting versions of reality",
    "b": "the issue of racism, immigration, and xenophobia",
    "c": "the pitfalls to patterns of dominance and control",
    "d": "the power of friendship and love",
    "e": "the relationship between technology and humanity",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the Aldebaranians be distinguished?",
    "a": "by their eyes",
    "b": "by their height",
    "c": "by their names",
    "d": "by their skin color",
    "e": "by their voices",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ennbe Ennbe gives George Orr a record of the song",
    "a": "“Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds”",
    "b": "“We Can Work It Out”",
    "c": "“With a Little Help From My Friends”",
    "d": "“Here Comes the Sun”",
    "e": "“Yellow Submarine”",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which character showed “pity and protective compassion” to George Orr after his ordeal with the Augmentor?",
    "a": "E’nememen Asfah",
    "b": "William Haber",
    "c": "Mannie Ahrens",
    "d": "Tiua’k Ennbe Ennbe",
    "e": "Heather Lelache",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal does Asfah resemble?",
    "a": "salamander",
    "b": "sea turtle",
    "c": "black widow",
    "d": "woodpecker",
    "e": "koala",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Asfah is the owner of a",
    "a": "kitchen equipment shop",
    "b": "tavern",
    "c": "restaurant",
    "d": "furniture store",
    "e": "secondhand store",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which key piece of advice does Asfah give to George Orr?",
    "a": "“There is time. There are returns. To go is to return.”",
    "b": "“You must take your destiny into your own hands.”",
    "c": "“But change need not unbalance you; life’s not a static object, after all. It’s a process.”",
    "d": "“The end justifies the means. But what if there never is an end? All we have is means.”",
    "e": "“What does it matter whether you call it real or dreams? It’s all one—isn’t it?”",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  }
]

